Nagoor Sharief Shaik

Full stack web and mobile developer

Hyderabad, Telangana Sharief@Sharief.me

9494998994

As full-stack web and mobile developer, I spend a lot of my time working on web applications, native Android Applications, and Node.js applications. I am comfortable going up and down the stack in order to implement a new feature or develop a product. I have more than 2 years of experience building consumer-facing software with proficiency in NodeJs, Javascript, Php, Android, and RESTful APIs. and I am keen to learn more and extend my skills in programming as well as product management. And moreover, I'm always hungry to learn more.

Frontend

Javascript (es5-es7), Typescript,

Angular/NgRx, React/Redux, VueJS/Vuex, RxJS

Html/Css/Sass, Grid/Flexbox, Bootstrap/Foundation/Bulma

Backend

NodeJS, Express, Php, Laravel, MongoDB/MySql, Redis, Restful APIs

Mobile

Android, Ionic 3/4, React Native

UI/UX

Adobe Photoshop, XD, InVision

Other

Firebase Realtime DB, Socket.io, Java, Amazon Web Services,

Git, Bitbucket, Jira, SCRUM

Willing to relocate to: Hyderabad, Telangana - Bangalore, Karnataka

Work Experience

Sr. Software Engineer

Turpy Mobile Apps Pvt. Ltd. - Hyderabad, Telangana January 2018 to Present

Design, build and maintain efficient, reusable, and reliable Frontend / Backend code with technologies of NodeJS, Php, Laravel, React / VueJS, Javascript Libraries, HTML, CSS, and JSON.

- Work with application developers for Implementing server-side logic into a client application
- Drive continuous adoption and integration of relevant new technologies into a design.
- Contribute in all phases of the development lifecycle and follow best practices (test-driven development, continuous integration, SCRUM, refactoring and code standards)
- Work on all phases of the development lifecycle, including continuous integration, tests deployment, and refactoring.
- Served as primary team lead for Playat Application

Developer

Kynatech Systems Pvt. Ltd

November 2016 to January 2018

Design, build, and maintain efficient, reusable, and reliable Frontend code with technologies of AngularJS, Javascript Libraries, HTML, CSS and JSON.

- Work with server side developer for Implementing server side logic into frontend
- Developed a large-scale JavaScript application using Angular 4
- Assisted the API team to produce good RESTful standards
- Help maintain code quality, organization and automatization.
- · Served as primary bug-fixer in frontend technologies

Web Developer

Turpy Mobile Apps Pvt. Ltd. - Hyderabad, Telangana

November 2014 to November 2016

Responsible for understanding user requirements, designing and developing the web application.

- Involved in creation of UI components
- Developing Mobile UI prototypes in HTML and CSS

Freelancer Web Developer

January 2013 to September 2014

Created Websites / Branding for Local business

• Main languages and technologies required: Javascript, jQuery, HTML, Css, Bootstrap, PHP

Graphic Designer

Sankar Digital Signs - Hyderabad, Telangana

April 2010 to December 2012

Education

B.Sc IT

Acharya Nagarjuna University

Skills

Jquery, RxJS, Web Development, Php, Javascript, Css, Vuex, ExpressJS, Laravel, NgRx, socket.io, Html5, VueJS, Mongodb, Redux, redis, NodeJS, Angularjs, ReactJs, Android, Mobile Application, XML, Socket.io

http://zakeer.me

Publications

PlayAt (Sport Ground/Court Booking APP)

PlayAt is a ground booking Mobile App for Sports enthusiasts around Hyderabad, Developed by Turpy Mobile Apps Pvt Ltd. PlayAt shows you nearby sports facilities and makes an instant booking of available playing slots. Users will get the notifications of the events happening at the Sports Arena Stack: Express, Node, React, VueJS, Socket.IO, Redis, MySql, Php (Laravel), Android

Label Verification Request System

The LVR system being built for IBTS allows for users to put in requests for Data Plates and/or Label Verification for manufactured homes. The product has an intuitive, web-based interface for external users to put in the request. The product also allows IBTS internal staff to process the request and issue the final letters and certificates via an online web-based fulfillment process.

Stack: Angular 4, Typescript, JavaScript, Html, CSS, Bootstrap

Zingo Credit

Zingo is a free, automated service that allow users to submit they recurring payments to the credit bureaus so they can receive credit for payments that are not traditionally included on your credit report.

Unlike traditional information included on user credit report – like mortgages and credit cards – Zingo brings users a new way to build or enhance there score without incurring additional debt. Stack: VueJS, MySql, Php (Laravel)

iNteliCode

iNteliCode is cashback campaign for book store. where student buy book and send cashback code from scratch label to receive cashback into their account.

Stack: ReactNative, VueJS, Redis, MySql, Php (Laravel)